mentor.com 2019-12-15

# Mentor Graphics Privacy Policy - Mentor Graphics

### How we treat your personal information

Mentor considers all information collected to be our information. It will be collected from you via the forms in various locations on Mentor Graphics websites and from your voluntary participation in product improvement programs, but will not be shared with, bartered, or sold to any third party without your consent.

We collect information from you for the purposes of fulfilling your requests, improving your experience on the Mentor Graphics websites, verify your identity, improving our ability to create individually relevant communications to you about our products and services and improving our products and features to help better solve design problems. You may choose to not supply any personal information to us; however, doing so will limit your access to certain content on our site, such as product demonstrations, white papers, and the like.

At times, we disclose relevant information about our customers to our contractors in order for them to provide specific services for Mentor, or to distributors to fulfill a customer order. Our contractors and distributors are bound by strict contractual requirements to keep all information they receive confidential and to use such information solely on behalf of Mentor Graphics. We take reasonable measures to protect the information you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure.

### How we treat email lists

Mentor Graphics maintains several e-mail lists to keep interested persons informed about events and other items of interest. Individuals can sign up to join our mailing lists in several ways, for example; in response to an email message or by using a form on our website. Other than disclosing to contractors as required for them to perform specific services for Mentor Graphics, we do not sell, trade, lease, rent, loan or otherwise disclose the addresses on these lists to any third party without your consent.

### Information change requests

We realize that your personal information, including name, company, and email address, is subject to change over time. if you need to update your information in our records, please send email to [ **Privacy@mentor.com**](mailto:privacy@mentor.com). 

If you are registered with Mentor Graphics’ profile center, you can update your data [**online**](https://signin.mentor.com/register?next=https%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Ementor%2Ecom%2Fterms_conditions%2Fprivacy).

### How we treat your browser information

Mentor Graphics analyzes the log files of our website to better understand the volume of traffic to particular areas of our site. This information helps us to serve your information needs. Individual users remain anonymous in our website log files unless they have logged into one of our password-protected sites.

For example, when accessing SupportNet, our technical support web site, we may correlate individual registration and browser information to your personal and company information as stored in our business databases. These databases contain support contract expiration dates and other information relevant to delivering and improving support.

### Our use of cookies

A "cookie" is a marker or an identifier that is entered into the memory of a visitor's browser and is saved to a file for future reference. Mentor Graphics uses cookies on selected areas of our website as a tool to "remember" information about our visitors so that they do not have to repeatedly enter their personal information onto numerous forms on the site.

In the future, cookies will help us tailor our website to the visitor's individual interests. You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie so that you can decide whether or not to accept it. Even without a cookie, you can access most information on our web site.

### How we treat information collected from a product improvement program

Technological features in our products and on our website may provide data to Mentor Graphics or its contractors and are used for the purpose of making improvements to products and enhancing features used most by our customers. Typically, the limited data collected includes information on product performance, settings, options, output log files, and similar product functionality.

Mentor Graphics analyzes this information along with data from other program participants to help improve user experience. Mentor Graphics will not collect any personally identifiable data in this process and will not disclose your data collected to any third party without your prior written consent, except to Mentor Graphics’ outside attorneys or as may be required by a court of competent jurisdiction.

### Transfer of Personal Information:

Mentor Graphics has its headquarters in the United States, so the information we collect from you maybe be processed in the United States.  Mentor Graphics takes suitable safeguards for the protection of your personal data.  Mentor Graphics participates in, complies with, and has certified its adherence to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and the United Kingdom to the United States. Mentor Graphics is committed to subjecting personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and the United Kingdom in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework and to the Framework’s applicable principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [**Privacy Shield List**](http://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome).

Sometimes the recipients to whom Mentor Graphics transfers your personal data are located in countries in which applicable laws do not offer the same level of data protection as the laws of your home country. In those cases, we will only transfer personal data to external recipients who have (1) entered into EU standard contractual clauses with Mentor Graphics, (2) implemented Binding Corporate Rules in its Organization or (3) U.S. companies that entered into the Privacy Shield self certification program. 

**Data Storage and Retention:**

We retain your personal data for the duration of the business relationship with Mentor Graphics.  We only store it for as long as the purposes for which the information was collected or otherwise processed, or to comply with legal obligations (such as Retention obligations under tax or Commercial laws).

**California Privacy Rights**

California’s “Shine The Light” law permits those of our customers who are California residents to annually request a list of their personal data (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year, and the names and addresses of those third parties. At this time, we currently do not share any personal data with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation provides certain rights to data subjects living in the EU.  Subject to the statutory requirements, EU citizens are entitled to:

  * Obtain confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning you are being processed, and where that is the case, access to the personal data;
  * Obtain the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning you;
  * Obtain the erasure of your personal data;
  * Obtain restriction of processing regarding your personal data;
  * Data portability concerning personal data, which you actively provided; and
  * Object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to processing of personal data concerning you.

### Complaint or Concerns:

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Mentor Graphics commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact us at [**dataprotection@siemens.com**](mailto:dataprotection@siemens.com) with "Privacy Request" in the subject line. Please provide a detailed description of your request or complaint so we can adequately respond.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [**https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield Website you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
